Register of the Fritz Machlup Papers, 1911-1983
Hoover Institution Archives
Fritz Machlup Papers,
1911-1983
83037
Machlup, Fritz, 1902-
313 manuscript boxes, 11 oversize boxes, 6 card file boxes, 1 album box, 4 phonotape cassettes, 4 phonotape reels (139 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, reports, memoranda, notes, questionnaires, data, financial records, grant proposals, instructional materials, and printed matter, relating to economic theory and to information systems and the creation and transmission of knowledge.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1983.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Economics.; Information services.; Learning and scholarship.; Economists.; Phonotapes.
Biographical Note
1902 December 15 Born, Wiener Neustadt, Austria
1922-1933 Partner and director, Timmersdorfer Holzstoff und Pappenfabrik Emerich Kren and Co., Vienna, Austria
1923 Dr. Rer. Pol., Universitat Wien, Vienna
1924-1933 Partner and managing director, Ybbstaler Pappenfabriken Adolf Leitner und Bruder, Vienna
1924-1948 Director, Elso Magyar Cartonlemezgyar Rt. (Erste Ungarische Carton-Pappenfabrik), Budapest, Hungary
1925 Author, Die Goldkernwahrung Married Marianne (Mitzi) Herzog
1927 Author, Die neuen Wahrungen in Europa
1929-1931 Council member, Austrian Cardboard Cartel, Vienna
1929-1933 Lecturer, Volkshochschule Wien, Vienna
1931 Author, Borsenkredit, Industriekredit und Kapitalbildung
1933 Moved to the United States
1933-1935 Research fellow, Rockefeller Foundation
1934 Author, Fuhrer durch die Krisenpolitik
1934-1935, 1938-1939 Visiting lecturer, Harvard University, Massachusetts
1935-1947 Frank H. Goodyear professor of economics, University of Buffalo, New York
1936 Visiting professor, Harvard University
1937-1938 Visiting professor, Cornell University, New York
1938 Visiting professor, Northwestern University, Illinois
1939 Visiting professor, University of California, Berkeley
1940 Naturalized American
1940, 1947 Visiting professor, Stanford University, California
1941 Visiting professor, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor
1942-1943 Special consultant, Post War Labor Problems Division, Bureau of Labor Statistics, United States Department of Labor
1943 Author, International Trade and the National Income Multiplier
1943-1946 Visiting professor, American University, Washington, D.C.
1943-1946 Chief, Research Section; Acting Chief, Division of Investigation and Research; Chief, Division of Research and Statistics, Office of Alien Property Custodian, Washington, D.C.
1947-1960 Abram G. Hutzler professor of political economy, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland
1948 Visiting professor, Columbia University, New York
1949 Visiting professor, University of California, Los Angeles Author, The Basing-Point System
1952 Author, The Political Economy of Monopoly Author, The Economics of Sellers' Competition
1955 Visiting professor, Kyoto University and Doshisha University, Japan Director, Kyoto American Studies Seminar
1957-1958 Research fellow, Ford Foundation
1958 Author, An Economic Review of the Patent System
1960-1971 Walker professor of economics and international finance, and director of the International Finance Section, Princeton Uniersity, New Jersey
1962 Author, The Production and Distribution of Knowledge in the United States
1963 Author, Essays in Economic Semantics
1963-1964 Visiting professor, City University of New York
1964 Author, International Payments, Debts, and Gold
1965-1977 Consultant, United States Department of the Treasury
1966 Author (with William J. Fellner, Robert Triffin, and eleven others), Maintaining and Restoring Balance in International Payments
1968 Author, Remaking the International Monetary System: The Rio Agreement and Beyond
1969-1971 Visiting professor, New York University
1970 Visiting professor, Osaka University, Japan and University of melbourne, Australia
1971-1983 Professor of economics, New York University
1972 Author (with Jan Tinbergen, Abram Bergson and Oskar Morgenstern), Optimum Social Welfare and Productivity Author, The Alignment of Foreign Exchange Rates
1972-1973 Visiting professor, Universitat Wien
1975 Author, International Monetary Systems
1976 Author, Selected Economic Writings of Fritz Machlup
1977 Author, A History of Thought on Economic Integration
1978 Author, Methodology of Economics and Other Social Sciences
1978 Author (with Kenneth W. Leeson et al.), Information through the Printed Word: The Dissemination of Scholarly, Scientific, and Intellectual Knowledge Volume I: Book Publishing Volume II: Journals Volume III: Libraries
1980 Volume IV: Books, Journals, and Bibliographic Sciences Author, Knowledge: Its Creation, Distribution, and Economic significance Volume I: Knowledge and knowledge Production
1982 Volume II: The Branches of Learning
1983 Volume III: The Economics of Information and Human Capital
1983 January 30 Died, Princeton, New Jersey
Series Description
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1902-1982. (Boxes 1-18.)
  Addresses, affidavits, bibliographies, biographies, clippings, correspondence, financial and other records, invitations, legal documents, letters of recommendation, lists, programs, reports, schedules, and tributes, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- CORRESPONDENCE, CHRONOLOGICAL, 1973-1983. (Boxes 19-21.)
  Day files arranged chronologically
- CORRESPONDENCE, ALPHABETICAL, 1933-1983. (Boxes 21-75.)
  Letters arranged alphabetically by correspondent
- NOTES, 1917-1983. (Boxes 76-80.)
  Notebooks and reading and research notes, arranged alphabetically by subject
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1911-1983. (Boxes 81-225.)
  Articles, conference papers, congressional testimony, drafts of books, essays, letters to the editor, notes, reviews, speeches, and related research material and correspondence, arranged chronologically by title
- RESEARCH PROJECTS (UNPUBLISHED), 1949-1982. (Boxes 226-228.)
  Research proposals, press releases, project descriptions, progress reports, financial statements and correspondence, arranged chronologically by title of project
- ACADEMIC CAREER, 1929-1983. (Boxes 229-274.)
  Correspondence, course material, curricula vitae, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, reports, and student files, arranged alphabetically by university and then by physical form
- OFFICE OF ALIEN PROPERTY CUSTODIAN, 1943-1946. (Boxes 275-278.)
  Governmental agency established by Congress in 1917 to deal with enemy-owned property in the United States. Correspondence, memoranda, monographs, and reports, by Fritz Machlup and others, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- MONT PELERIN SOCIETY, 1946-1983. (Boxes 279-281.)
  Correspondence, bylaws, circulars, memoranda, minutes of meetings, newsletters, reports, and publications, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- GROUP OF THIRTY (CONSULTATIVE GROUP ON INTERNATIONAL ECONOMIC AND MONETARY AFFAIRS), 1963-1982 (Boxes 282-285.)
  Group of academic economists and officials from national monetary authorities and international agencies. Correspondence, financial records, memoranda, and minutes of meetings, arranged chronologically by the various names under which the Group was known (Bellagio Group, Joint Conference of Officials and Academics on International Monetary Reform, Group of Thirty) and then alphabetically by physical form
- BURGENSTOCK GROUP, 1968-1971. (Box 285.)
  Group of officials, academics, and practitioners from multinational business and finance, concerned solely with the question of greater flexibility of exchange rates. Correspondence, memoranda, and minutes of meetings, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- AMERICAN ASSOCIATION OF UNIVERSITY PROFESSORS, 1952-1982. (Boxes 286-288.)
  Correspondence, lists, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, reports, studies, statements, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- AMERICAN ECONOMIC ASSOCIATION, 1935-1982. (Boxes 289-291.)
  Correspondence, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, reports, statements, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- INTERNATIONAL ECONOMIC ASSOCIATION, 1951-1983. (Boxes 291-298.)
  Correspondence, financial records, memoranda, minutes of meetings, notes, reports, and newsletters, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- SUBJECT FILE, 1914-1982. (Boxes 299-311.)
  Conference papers, correspondence, memoranda, notes, press releases, speeches, statements, reports, studies, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject
- WRITINGS BY OTHERS, 1927-1981. (Boxes 311-313.)
  Conference papers, essays, journal articles, and speeches, arranged alphabetically by author
- INDEX CARD FILE, n.d. (Boxes 314-319.)
  Address and book order files, and reading and research notes arranged alphabetically by subject
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1922-1982. (Boxes 320-328.)
  Bound volumes of speeches and writings referred to in the bibliography compiled by Fritz Machlup's assistant, and scrapbooks of clippings relating to Fritz Machlup and family
- MEMORABILIA, 1923-1982. (Boxes 329-330.)
  Awards, certificates, citations, commemorative albums, honorary degrees, medals, and plaques
- SOUND RECORDINGS, 1973-1981. (Cassette cabinet; tape cabinet)
  Phonotapes and phonotape cassettes of speeches and of dictation of correspondence and writings, arranged chronologically by title
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1947-1974. (Photo file)
  See photo card catalog
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1902-1982.
  See also OVERSIZE MATERIAL
  - Addresses (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Articles about or mentioning Fritz Machlup
    - Undated (Folder 3)
    - 1930s-1940s (Folder 4)
    - 1960s (Folder 5)
    - 1970s (Folder 6)
    - 1980s (Folder 7)
  - Bibliographies (Folder 8-9)
  - Biographies (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Birth certificate (Folder 3)
  - Book orders (Folder 4)
  - Business cards (Folder 5)
  - Business records relating to Fritz Machlup's business partnerships in Austria and Hungary. Includes correspondence with Eugen (Jeno) Binetter.
    See also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, Subject file, Family, Srul Osterer and Jacob Wolf
    - 1927-1941 (Folder 6)
    - 1934-1938 (Folder 7-8)
    - 1935-1937 (Folder 9)
    - 1945-1957 (Folder 10)
  - Circular letter to friends describing the move to Johns Hopkins University, 1947 (Folder 11)
  - Distribution lists for various books and articles (Folder 12)
  - Employment records. For academic appointments
    See ACADEMIC CAREER
    - United States. Department of Labor, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Office of Alien Property Custodian, 1943-1946 (Folder 2)
    - State of Maryland Commission for the Study of the Public Service Commission Law (Sklar Commission), 1952-1953. Includes correspondence with Albert L. Sklar and Robert Solo (Folder 3)
    - United States. Department of the Treasury, 1965-1977 (Folder 4)
  - Fan and hate mail (Folder 5)
  - Financial records, relating to Fritz Machlup's holdings in Europe and the United States
    - 1925 (Folder 6)
    - 1933-1937 (Folder 7)
    - 1934-1938 (Folder 8)
    - 1936-1939 (Folder 9)
    - 1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - 1937-1948 (Folder 3)
    - 1938-1941 (Folder 4)
    - 1943-1944 (Folder 5)
  - Home ownership records (Folder 6-7)
  - Insurance records (Folder 8-12)
  - Invitations for speaking engagements and written contributions (declined)
    - 1958-1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 1964 (Folder 2)
    - 1965 (Folder 3)
    - 1966 (Folder 4)
    - 1967 (Folder 5)
    - 1968 (Folder 6)
    - 1969 (Folder 7)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 1973-1976 (Folder 2)
    - 1977-1979 (Folder 3)
    - 1980-1982 (Folder 4)
  - Letters of recommendation
    - By Fritz Machlup. For recommendations of students
      See ACADEMIC CAREER, General
      - 1938-1957 (Folder 5)
      - 1961-1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - For Fritz Machlup, 1934-1941
      - Burbank, H. H. (Folder 2)
      - Epstein, Ralph C. (Folder 3)
      - Frankfurter, Felix (Folder 4)
      - May, Stacy (Folder 5)
      - Mises, Ludwig von (Folder 6)
      - Park, Julian (Folder 7)
      - Young, Arthur H. (Folder 8)
  - Lists
    - Journals for review copies (Folder 9)
    - Lectures, panel discussions, and seminars, 1936-1965 (Folder 10)
    - Selected topics for special lectures in international finance (Folder 11)
    - Work priorities, 1963-1982 (Folder 12)
  - Litigation records (Folder 13)
  - Medical records (Folder 14-17)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 18)
  - Moving records (Folder 19)
  - Programs of conferences and other events attended by Fritz Machlup
    - General
      - 1920s-1930s (Folder 20)
      - 1940s-1950s (Folder 21)
      - 1960s (Folder 22)
      - 1971 (Folder 23)
      - 1972 (Folder 24)
      - 1973 (Folder 25)
      - 1974-1977 (Folder 26)
      - 1978-1979 (Folder 27)
      - 1980s (Folder 28)
    - Allied Social Science Associations, 1933-1972 (Folder 8)
    - Allied Social Science Associations, 1973-1982 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - American Association of University Professors, 1959-1968 (Folder 4)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1964-1977 (Folder 5)
    - Econometric Society, 1933-1965 (Folder 6)
    - Southern Economic Association, 1953-1974 (Folder 7)
  - Questions and math riddles, including those sent to radio quiz programs (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Requests by others
    - Reprints (Folder 2)
    - Reproduction and translation permissions (Folder 3-4)
  - Schedules (Folder 5)
  - School records, 1913-1932 (Folder 6)
  - Stories and jokes (Folder 7)
  - Subject file
    - Assistance to
      - European refugees, 1938-1946
        - General (Folder 8)
        - Affidavits by Fritz Machlup and others for the following people and their families. Includes correspondence
          - Albrecht, Gretel (sister-in-law) (Folder 9)
          - Balint, Helene (sister) (Folder 10)
          - Deutsch, Alice (friend) (Folder 11)
          - Dukes, Salomon (friend) (Folder 12)
          - Gelles, Viktor.
            See Taubmann, Juda
          - Gottfried, Alois (friend) (Folder 13)
          - Herzog, Gisela (mother-in-law) (Folder 14)
          - Kritzler, Johanna (friend) (Folder 15)
          - Kupfer, Adele (friend) (Folder 16)
          - Langer, Rudolf (friend) (Folder 17)
          - Leitner, Alfred (nephew) (Folder 18)
          - Leitner, Lona (sister). (Folder 19)
            See also Balint, Helene
          - Leitner, Felix.
          - Machlup, Eduard (cousin) (Folder 20)
          - Machlup, Gustav F. (brother) (Folder 21)
          - Neuspiel, Erich (cousin) (Folder 22)
          - Rauchberg, William Sigmund (cousin) (Box 11, Folder 1)
          - Sharman, Michael H. (friend) (Folder 2)
          - Singer, Rudolf (friend) (Folder 3)
          - Spitz, Lily (friend) (Folder 4)
          - Steiner, Johanna (aunt) (Folder 5)
          - Taubmann, Juda (Folder 6)
        - Correspondence
          - General (mainly unanswered or declined requests) (Folder 7-9)
          - Hebrew Sheltering and Immigrant Aid Society of America, 1939-1942 (Folder 10)
        - Financial statements of Fritz Machlup in support of his affidavits (Folder 11)
        - List of people assisted (Folder 12)
      - Czech and Polish emigres, 1968-1982.
        See also Trips, Czechoslovakia and Poland, 1967
        - Correspondence relating to efforts by Fritz Machlup and others to relocate Czech and Polish scholars in the West
          - General (Folder 13)
          - American Council of Learned Societies (Gordon B. Turner) (Folder 14)
          - Ford Foundation (Peter E. de Janosi, Howard R. Swearer) (Folder 15)
          - Ifo-Institut fur Wirtschaftsforschung (Eduard Werle) (Folder 16)
          - Osterreichisches Institut fur Wirtschaftsforschung (Franz Nemschak) (Folder 17)
          - Wiener Institut fur Internationale Wirtschaftsvergleiche (Friedrich Levcik) (Folder 18)
          - With various American universities (Folder 19)
        - Emigre files. Correspondence, curricula vitae, and notes
          - Balcar, Jan (Box 12, Folder 1)
          - Blass, Bronislaw (Folder 2)
          - Bognar, Jozsef (Folder 3)
          - Broner, Adam. (Folder 4)
            See also Zachariasz, Jerzy
          - Budinova, Rita (Folder 5)
          - Cerny, Martin (Folder 6)
          - Choynacka, Helena (Folder 7)
          - Drewnowski, Jan (Folder 8)
          - Goldmann, Josef (Folder 9)
          - Gomulka, Stanislaw (Folder 10)
          - Heretik, Stefan (Folder 11)
          - Hrncir, Miroslaw (Folder 12)
          - Kierzkowski, Henryk (Folder 13)
          - Kochanski, Zdzislaw (Folder 14)
          - Kosta, H. G. J. (Folder 15)
          - Kosta, J. J. (Folder 16)
          - Kouba, Karel (Folder 17)
          - Kratky, Bohumil (Folder 18)
          - Laski, Kazimierz (Folder 19)
          - Levcik, Bedrich (Folder 20)
          - Lobl, Eugen (Folder 21)
          - Martinova, Georgina (Folder 22)
          - Martinova, Katka (Folder 23)
          - Mianecki, Pawel (Folder 24)
          - Mladek, Jiri (Folder 25)
          - Nagy, Tibor (Folder 26)
          - Nesvera, Vaclav (Folder 27)
          - Orlowski, Miroslaw (Folder 28)
          - Pokorny, Dusan (Folder 29)
          - Rychetnik, Ludek (Folder 30)
          - Schermer, Henry (Folder 31)
          - Selucky, Radoslav (Folder 32)
          - Sereghyova, Jana (Folder 33)
          - Sik, Ota (Folder 34)
          - Silhan, Venek (Folder 35)
          - Slama, Jiri. (Folder 36)
            See also Vogel, Heinrich
          - Stadnik, Milos (Folder 37)
          - Tardos, M. (Folder 38)
          - Temkin, Gabriel. (Folder 39)
            See also Blass, Bronislaw
          - Turcan, Pavol (Folder 40)
          - Turek, Otakar (Folder 41)
          - Vogel, Heinrich (Folder 42)
          - Vysusil, Georg (Folder 43)
          - Zachariasz, Jerzy (Folder 44)
          - Zielinski, Janusz G. (Folder 45)
          - Zwass, Adam (Folder 46)
    - Birthdays. Cards, correspondence, invitation lists, tributes, and clippings
      - 70th (1972) (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - 75th (1977) (Folder 2)
      - 80th (1982) (Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 4)
    - Death, 1983 January 30
      - Condolence letters (Folder 5-8)
      - Correspondence of Rosa L. Schupbach, Fritz Machlup's secretary at New York University, 1983 January-June (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Memorial invitation list (Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous (Folder 3)
      - Tributes (Folder 4)
    - Decorations - Grosses Silbernes Ehrenzeichen mit dem Stern fur Verdienste um die Republik Osterreich, 1978 February. Correspondence with Walter Brunner, Heinz Kienzl, Stephan Koren, Phillip Rieger, Heinrich Treichl (Folder 5)
    - Dissertation (Folder 6)
    - Family. Correspondence, family trees, legal documents
      - General. (Folder 7)
        See also Joachim, Susanne
      - Albrecht, Gretel (sister-in-law) and Paul, 1938-1951 (Folder 8)
      - Allina, Helen (sister-in-law) and Erich and Franz, 1938-1977 (Folder 9)
      - Balint, Helena (sister), 1938-1939 (Folder 10)
      - Balint, Ilona (niece), 1939-1948 (Folder 11)
      - Braun, Franziska Joachim (cousin), 1940-1941 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Braun, Gustav (cousin), 1976-1980. Includes correspondence with Alicia Braun. (Folder 2)
      - Frank, Charles E. (cousin), 1940-1942 (Folder 3)
      - Illing, Peter (cousin) and Maxine, 1937-1967. Includes correspondence with Erika Kuhtreiber (Folder 4)
      - Joachim, Susanne (cousin), 1938-1976 (Folder 5-8)
      - Lachowick, Hedwig (cousin), 1936-1946 (Folder 9)
      - Leitner, Lona (sister) and Fred, Georg, and Philipp. Includes correspondence with Felix Leitner, Gustav Leitner, Josef Leitner, Moritz Leitner, and Gustav F. Machlup
        - 1938-1943 (Folder 10)
        - 1944-1975 (Folder 11)
      - Machlup, Adolf (cousin) and Erna, 1940-1959 (Folder 12)
      - Machlup, Eduard (cousin) and Therese, 1938-1967 (Folder 13)
      - Machlup, Gustav F. (brother) and Olly
        - 1934-1940. Includes correspondence with Cecile Machlup (mother) (Box 16, Folder 1)
        - 1941-1947 (Folder 2)
        - 1954-1957 (Folder 3)
        - 1968 (Folder 4)
      - Machlup, Hanna (daughter), 1938-1976 (Folder 5)
      - Machlup, Mitzi (wife)
        - 1933 (Folder 6)
        - 1947 (Folder 7)
        - 1950 (Folder 8)
        - 1951 (Folder 9)
      - Machlup, Stefan (son)
        - 1942-1963 (Folder 10)
        - 1974-1977 (Folder 11)
        - 1978-1982 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Neuspiel, Rudolph and Grete (cousins), 1938-1952 (Folder 2)
      - Osterer, Srul (brother-in-law) and Friedrich, 1935-1961. Includes correspondence with Rudolph Neuspiel and other relatives (Folder 3)
      - Wolf, Jacob (adoptive father), 1934-1964. Includes correspondence with Heinrich and Renee Kiwe, Otto and Lucy Klater, Gustav F. Machlup, and Wilhelm Vogler (Folder 4)
    - Fencing (Folder 5)
    - Financial loan to Earl G. Broderick. Correspondence, 1960--1964 (Folder 6)
    - Fritz Machlup Fellowship Fund (Folder 7)
    - Immigration to the United States. Correspondence, 1935-1938 (Folder 8)
    - Honorary degrees. Correspondence and programs
      - Lawrence College, Appleton, Wisconsin, 1956 June 10 (Folder 9)
      - Christian-Albrechts-Universitat, Kiel, Germany, 1965 June 2 (Folder 10)
      - Lehigh University, Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, 1967 June 12 (Folder 11)
      - Case Institute of Technology, Cleveland, Ohio, 1967 June 13 (Folder 12)
      - La Salle College, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1968 October 27 (Folder 13)
      - Universitat Wien, Vienna, Austria, 1971 June 17 (Folder 14)
      - Hochschule St. Gallen fur Wirtschafts- und Sozialwissenschaften, St. Gallen, Switzerland, 1972 June 17 (Folder 15)
    - Library
      - Sale of periodicals, 1972-1983 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Disposition of books, 1983 (Folder 2)
    - Military service (Folder 3)
    - Presidency of the Austrian National Bank, Offer of the. Memorandum to the files, notes, clippings, and correspondence with the Osterreichische Nationalbank (Reinhard Kamitz, Andreas Korp, Herbert Prack, Wolfgang Schmitz) and Friedrich A. von Hayek, Josef Klaus, Robert Triffin, and the United States Department of State and Department of the Treasury, 1966-1971 (Folder 4)
    - Religion (Folder 5)
    - Skiing (Folder 6)
    - Translation of books (Folder 7)
    - Trips
      - Mexico, 1950. Correspondence (Folder 8)
      - Japan, Asia, Middle East, 1955. Notes (Folder 9)
      - Germany, 1959. Correspondence and notes (Folder 10)
      - Brazil, 1965
        - Correspondence
          - Fundacco Getulio Vargas (Folder 11)
          - United States A.I.D. (Agency for International Development) Mission to Brazil (Folder 12)
        - Report (Folder 13)
      - Czechoslovakia and Poland, 1967
        - General (Folder 14)
        - Correspondence with United States. Department of State (Folder 15)
        - Notes (Folder 16)
        - Report (Folder 17)
      - Japan, 1970 April-June
        - General (Folder 18)
        - Correspondence with the Committee on International Exchange of Persons and the United States Educational Commission in Japan (Fulbright Commission) (Folder 19)